<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GCP on Andrea Dodet</title>
    <link>https://anddt.com/categories/gcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GCP on Andrea Dodet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2021 Andrea dodet</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anddt.com/categories/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with CI for Google Cloud Functions Monorepo</title>
      <link>https://anddt.com/post/ci-cloudfunctions-monorepo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anddt.com/post/ci-cloudfunctions-monorepo/</guid>
      <description>Sensible CI for a Google Cloud Function monorepo For the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working for a client that has been around for long enough to have amassed a fair bit of technical debt. After observing for quite some time team dynamics I believe the main root causes can be summarised as:
 High employee turnover. Non tecnical Product Managers/Owners. Lack of documentation on multiple levels (both technical and business).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting simple scripts for cheap on GCP</title>
      <link>https://anddt.com/post/gcp-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anddt.com/post/gcp-functions/</guid>
      <description>Hosting simple scripts for cheap on GCP On giving an old Macbook Air some rest In the past few weeks I wanted to get a sense of how many remote-friendly jobs are posted on stackoverflow on a given day. To do this, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a small Python utility that parses their XML feed and uploads the results on a spreadsheet on Google Drive. So far so good.
I initially hosted this script as a crontab job on my old Macbook Air that sits collecting dust on a bookshelf.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
